Higgins mss., 1951-1964 LMC 1496
Lilly Library
Higgins mss.
1951-1964
Lilly Library
Higgins, Brian, 1930-1965
LMC 1496
1 Box 1 standard
The Higgins mss., 1951-1964, are the correspondence and writings of Brian Higgins, 1930-1965, poet.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Brian Higgins, 1930-1965, was a poet, professional rugby player, and mathematician. He worked briefly as a schoolteacher and a freelance journalist, and died at the age of 35 before his third book of poems was released.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of the correspondence and writings of Brian Higgins, 1930-1965. They include his poems and a letter and the letters of Roy Campbell to Higgins.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 1961
English Poetry; Higgins, Brian, 1930-1965
- Notebook of early works which Higgins "most wanted to preserve", 1952-1960 (Box 1)
- "Two poems in the snow," undated (Box 1)
- "To the man who died while attempting to swim the English Channel," undated (Box 1)
- "To G.C.," undated (Box 1)
- "To a child with a Christmas sphere," undated (Box 1)
- "Terminus," undated (Box 1)
- "Suffering the crass explosions of morning," undated (Box 1)
- "Words against Newton," undated (Box 1)
- "We rise with music to the frigid morn," undated (Box 1)
- Note on publication of Higgins's poems, undated (Box 1)
- Notes on "The North," undated (Box 1)
- "Number none: a dance of zeros," undated (Box 1)
- "On going to the city," undated (Box 1)
- "The only need," undated (Box 1)
- "Poem to a Catholic lock forward," undated (Box 1)
- "Should poets be political," undated (Box 1)
- "The social realists," undated (Box 1)
- "The collier," undated (Box 1)
- "Epithalamium," undated (Box 1)
- "How I felt in an hotel on the Ataturk Boulevard, Ankara," undated (Box 1)
- "I am that man whose burdened days are spent," undated (Box 1)
- "Inanition," undated (Box 1)
- "Leave your home behind lad," undated (Box 1)
- "Mercy on us I was taught of war," undated (Box 1)
- "My mother was a burler," undated (Box 1)
- "National service," undated (Box 1)
- Notebook - materials laid in, 27 December 1951-6 August 1964 (Box 1)
- Campbell, Roy. To Higgins, Brian, 3 April 1956 (Box 1)
- Campbell, Roy. To Higgins, Brian, 20 July 1956 (Box 1)
- Campbell, Roy. To Higgins, Brian, 28 December 1956 (Box 1)
- Higgins, Brian. To "Gerard", June 1959 (Box 1)
- "And so we fall," undated (Box 1)
- "Anti-solar hymn," undated (Box 1)
- "Cartons," undated (Box 1)
- "The North," undated (Box 1)
- Campbell, Roy. To Higgins, Brian, undated (Box 1)